How did um your your past I you played
uh you were a Wildcat quarterback. How
how does that kind of help you? Um how
did that kind of help you when you
transition to being a full-time tight
end?
>> Yeah, so I mean as you know like I
started playing quarterback in freshman
year of college. Um and and I made the
switch. I played quarterback all
throughout high school. Um but just
conceptually knowing the game um seeing
the picture. Um just kind of knowing
everything just kind of helped me out
when you know you kind of want to know
everybody's everybody's position at
quarterback. then going to tight end
knowing just your position. So, it's
kind of slowed it down for me, I would
say.
>> And I know that like um I know Baker
uses the the words quarterback friendly
a lot when when talking about different
targets. So, like your time there being
a quarterback, how can that make you a a
more um
>> quarterback friendly target yourself?
>> Yeah, I mean that's my main goal is just
to just to pick his brain. I mean,
there's so much utter respect for that
man. Um seriously, just being the QB1 of
the team. Um, but just can't wait to
just just earn earn my earn my trust to
him on the on the roll on offense and
just be be what I like to say is a
blanket to him. Just a friendly blanket
just to cover him up when stuff goes to
stuff goes to crap. Um um just to just
to be that guy for him. So
>> B, congratulations. Uh just wanted to
ask what level of interest did the Bucks
have in you throughout the pre-draft
process?
>> They had a lot. You know, I took a
visit, took a 30 visit there. Um met
with the coach. I had I don't
I don't want to say I had a Zoom call,
but I had a 30 visit, so I I knew they
were definitely interested. So,
>> And how did that 30 visit go for you?
>> It was awesome. I mean, just the vibes
down there. Um, my guy Ty that was
taking me around, worked at LSU
previously, so just kind of know him, it
just it just fit, man. It was awesome.
>> What are some parts of your game as a
tight end uh that you're very proud of
at the college level that you think will
translate really well to the NFL level?
>> I'm just very versatile player. You can
put me at fullback. Um, you can put me
as a Y tight end, you put me as an H, it
doesn't really matter. Um, I can do it
all. Um, you ask me to go run them on
kick off and make a tack, I'm going to
do that as well. You know, all the
special teams, I think I'm just a I'm
just a Swiss Army knife, as they would
say, playing um, walk out QB my
sophomore year. So, yes, sir.
>> What was that moment like for you? Were
there emotions when you got that call
when you looked down and saw that 813
number?
>> I don't think there's any tears left in
my my my body. I think they all just got
out like everyone was crowded. It was
awesome just to just kind of, you know,
I I was fortunate for one offer out of
high school to play quarterback. Now I'm
here in NFL tight end. So that's just a
testament to how go good God is in my
life. So
>> are you in Dothan right now?
>> I am. Yes, sir.
>> Yeah. How is it? How is Dothan up there?
>> It's awesome. We got surprise draft
party I had no idea about at six
o'clock. So we'll go we'll go celebrate
that.
>> What What So what did you think you were
doing today then? I was just like, "Mom,
I just wanted all family. Like, let's
just do family the agent." So,
here we go. We're six o'clock. A couple
hours we're going to see her.
>> Are you okay handling surprises? I mean,
sometimes you have to
>> Yeah. I mean, I know now, so it's not
really a surprise, but it it was good.
>> Ber, given your frame and the fact that
you benched 20 reps at the NFL combine,
how do you feel about being a blocker at
the next level and kind of taking on
those tough assignments?
>> Yeah, I mean, I wouldn't even say
they're tough. They're they're um
inviting. I would say 20 was not my
number I I I was wanting. There's it's a
little low for me, I would say. But um
I'm just excited to learn and just to
just to be a sponge to the tight ending
coach and and the vets in that room,
honestly. Just um as a rookie coming in,
but I just I'm just trying to earn the
respect from my teammates to be honest
with you right off the jump and then
just go to work. Earn respect by the
work I put in.
>> What number did you have in mind?
>> Anything that's available
for the Ben
Oh. Oh. For the bench press. Oh, I mean
mid 20s. I I don't I have no idea. I
mean, I was just I thought I was going
to get more than 20, but it's all right.
>> On the spectrum of tight ends from from
pass catching tight ends to to block
first tight ends, do do you put yourself
in the middle? Is it something where
you're confident with both sides of it?
>> Say that one more time.
>> On the spectrum of tight ends, from
blocking tight ends to pass catching
tight ends, do you do you kind of put
yourself in the middle where you're
confident in both sides of it?
>> Oh, absolutely. I think I'm one of the
most versatile um tight ends in the
draft. I really do. just my twitchiness,
the top of routes, and I like to create
separation, but also the physicality and
the twitch right off the ball to um go
make a block for win a touchdown.
>> One of the unique things about being
like in the NIL era is you do see guys,
you know, jump around to different
schools and for you, how did each
destination that you arrived at, how did
that shape the player you are right now?
>> Yeah, I mean it was all meant to be. I
wouldn't trade it for the world. um
everywhere I went just the relationships
that I created uh helped me help mold me
into the man I am today along with my
heavenly father Jesus but um it was
awesome each stop I learned a lot um and
began to be groomed as a as a tight end
>> your mentality on the field especially
when you're when you know you have a run
blocking assignment but what kind of
edge and attitude do you like to play
with
>> I'm going to be willing to die for the
block right off the bat I mean there
there is no really uh really any other
way any other words to put it Um, I'm
I'm going to I'm going to be successful
this block. That's all that that's the
nicest way to put it.
>> B, do you happen to know anybody on the
roster? Anybody in that tight end room
currently in Tampa?
>> I do not. I do not. I know. I mean, I'm
familiar with the tight ends they got,
but um I I personally don't know
anybody.
>> Maybe catching some passes from Baker
Mayfield though.
>> That would uh Boomer baby I guess a
couple years ago running it back. That'd
be that'd be sick. I'm excited to meet
him.
By ask your given name isn't Ber as can
if you can say is that a family name.
How' you get the nickname Bower?
>> Uh that's my great-grandparents last
name. Um it's actually a middle name. I
go by William Bower. Um everybody either
calls him Bower or just we're just
playing on sharp. So that's what it is.
>> If you had a message for the Bucks fans
who are watching this right now, what
kind of player what kind of person are
they getting in you?
>> Yeah, I would just say I'm a go-getter.
I'm gonna do anything for for my
teammates. I'm I'm in love with my
teammates. Um, seriously, like I really
do. Um, I'm going to I'm passionate. Um,
I'm I'm a little crazy when I put the
helmet on, but I'm going to do anything
for um for Bucks Nation and everybody
around me.
>> You mentioned um you mentioned your
faith a little bit already. Just what
role did that play uh in this whole
journey for you?
>> Yeah, I mean, obviously as a football
player, you go through adversity that
any everyone anyone and everyone does.
So, that's kind of my main um vent is is
my faith. Um, obviously my family too,
but that's kind of what's got me through
and got me got me here today.
>> Anything else?
>> I appreciate I appreciate
>> Thank you very much. Nice meeting you.
>> Thanks.
Appreciate